Abdelrahman Awais Shaban - CV

Address: October 6 City, Giza Governorate, Egypt | ■ abdoawais10@gmail.com |

🛅 abdelrahman-a-shaban | 🞧 AbdelrahmanAwais | 🥒 +01010152093

CAREEROBJECTIVE

Looking for a position as a IT Help Desk. Bringing a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science and 6 years of help desk experience to provide technical support to clients/users facing Windows, internet, and hardware and software problems, installing hardware and software modules, setting up accounts in Active Directory to troubleshoot a broad variety of hardware and software issues.

PERSONALINFORMATION

Full Name: Abdelrahman Awais Shaban AbdelHamid

Gender: Male

Date of Birth: September 15, 1997

Military Service: Postponed

Marital Status: Married

Occupation: Fresh Graduate

EDUCATIONALBACKGROUND

AHRAM CANADIAN UNIVERSITY (ACU)

2015-2019

Bachelor's Degree of Computer Science in Computer Networks (GPA Very Good 3.26 / 4)

EXPERIENCE

Technical Support Agent

March 2021 - Current

At WE [Telecom Egypt]

• Call center agent to solve the technical queries of "WE" Customers over the phone.

Customer Service Agent

January 2020 - July 2020

At Orange

- · Gave customers the correct advice.
- Assisted in training new members of staff.
- Maintained a friendly manner and calm, positive demeanour when handling complaints.

INTERNSHIPSANDTRAININGS

MCSE: Private and Public Cloud Computing

January 2021 – February 2021

At National Telecommunication Institute (NTI)

- 20745: Implementing a Software-Defined Datacenter.
- 20703-1A: Administering System Center Configuration Manager.
- AZ-104: Microsoft Azure Administrator.

MCSA: Windows Server 2016

December 2020 - January 2021

At National Telecommunication Institute (NTI)

- 20740: Installation, Storage, and Compute with Windows Server 2016.
- 20741: Networking with Windows Server 2016.
- 20742: Identity with Windows Server 2016.

Android Developer Track

April 2018

At UDACITY (One Million Arab Coders Initiative)

TECHNICALSKILLS

Networking: CCNA Routing and Switching, MCSA, MCSE

Programming Languages: Python, C/C++, SQL, JavaScript, HTML/CSS

Developer Tools: Jupyter Notebooks, NetBeans, Adobe Photoshop CC 2018, Android Studio,

Notepad++, Visual Studio Code.

Networking Simulation Tools: Cisco Packet Tracer, VMware.

KEYSKILLS COMPETENCIES

- Responds to, resolves or escalates trouble calls/support requests via telephone, email, Service Desk Ticketing System, or Web.
- Provides technical support and troubleshooting to users.
- Strong computer skills including proficiency in MS Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint).
- Conflict resolution skills.
- Identifying, researching and troubleshooting IT issues.
- Good Ability to handle high pressure situations.
- Excellent computer troubleshooting skills with the ability to effectively diagnose, research and implement solutions to IT problems.
- Experience in Active Directory administration (creating/disabling accounts, etc.).
- Familiar with network troubleshooting including diagnosing end user connection issues, adding printers, etc.

LANGUAGES

English: Good in speaking and very good in reading and writing.

REFERENCES

Mina Anis

Team Leader, CC Call Center, Customer Care, Orange company

E-mail: Mina.ghaly@orange.com Mobile No.: +20 01227905258